oregon.gov 2004-12-16

# E-Government Privacy and Terms and Conditions

Links to Other Sites - A Disclaimer  
This site has links to other web sites as a convenience to our customers. These include links to web sites operated by other government agencies, nonprofit organizations and private businesses. When you use one of these links, you are no longer on this site and this Privacy Notice will not apply. When you link to another web site, you are subject to the privacy policy of that new site.  
When you follow a link to one of these sites neither the State of Oregon, nor any agency, officer, or employee of the State of Oregon warrants the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of any information published by these external sites, nor endorses any content, viewpoints, products, or services linked from these systems, and can not be held liable for any losses caused by reliance on the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of their information. Portions of such information may be incorrect or not current. Any person or entity that relies on any information obtained from these systems does so at his or her own risk.

Information Collected When You Just Browse  
If you do nothing during your visit to this web site but browse or download information, we automatically collect and store the standard data collected by all web server software. That information is as follows:  
1. The Internet Protocol (IP) address and domain name used (but not the e-mail address). The IP address is a numerical identifier assigned either to your Internet service provider or directly to your computer. We use the Internet IP to respond to your browser request.  Example: 122.125.36.42;  
2. The Domain domain name (DNS) assigned on the Internet to your IP Address (if there is one).  Example:   somename.com;  
3. The type of browser and operating system you used.  Example:  Mozilla/4.0 (compatible; MSIE 4.01; Windows NT; IE4WDUS-1998101501);  
4. The date and time you visited this site;  
5. The web pages or services you accessed at this site; and  
6. The web site you visited prior to coming to this web site. (Note: this is included so that summary analysis can be done on how visitors get to your site, i.e., from a search engine, from a link on another site, etc.)  
We do not track individual user navigation choices. We do, however, summarize the information listed above to determine:

  * what organizations are our most frequent users (item 2 above) to better target our content for the audience.

  * what browsers are being used on our site to determine what techniques we can use to develop pages that will work with different browsers (item 3 above).  

  * how often our pages are being used (item 5 above).

  * by the traffic from organization names such things as the search engines that are good at directing people to the site (item 6 above)

For site security purposes and to ensure that this service remains available to all users, this site may monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage. If security monitoring reveals evidence of possible abuse or criminal activity, system personnel may provide the results of such monitoring to appropriate officials. Except for authorized law enforcement investigations no attempts are made to identify individual users or their usage habits. Unauthorized attempts to upload information or change information on this service are strictly prohibited and may be punishable under the state law and federal statutes including the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986 and the National Information Infrastructure Protection Act of 1996.

Public Disclosure

All information collected at this site becomes a public record unless an exemption in law exists. ORS Chapter 192 contains the Oregon Public Records Law. and other program specific ORS's and OAR's.  
In the State of Oregon, laws exist to ensure that government is open and that the public has a right to access appropriate records and information possessed by state government. At the same time, there are exceptions to the public's right to access public records that serve various needs including the privacy of individuals. Both state and federal laws provide exceptions. We may request personally identifiable information from you in order to provide requested services, but such information is handled as it would be on an in-person visit to a governmental office.

Personal Information and Nondisclosure

"Personal information" is information about a natural person that is readily identifiable to that individual, such as an individual's name, address and telephone number. Such personal information may be exempt from disclosure if disclosure would constitute an unreasonable invasion of privacy under the circumstances. A domain name or Internet Protocol (IP) address is not considered personal information. Most information collected by state government is assumed to be open to the public unless specifically exempted.  ORS Chapter 192 contains the Oregon Public Records Law.  Under this law, individuals are permitted to request that public officials not disclose a public record that contains their home address and telephone number under certain circumstances. ORS 192.445 specifies how to request non-disclosure.

Email

If you send us an electronic mail message with a question or comment that contains personal information, or fill out a form that e-mails us this information, we will only use the information needed to respond to your request. We may redirect your message to another government agency that is in a better position to answer your question.  
The information collected is subject to the access and confidentiality provisions of the Oregon law including ORS Chapter192.

Forms

Each electronic form that collects personal information on this site will have a specific privacy statement or a link to the privacy statement that explains the conditions (if any) under which information may be shared with other parties.  
Requesting Personal Information Inspection  
You have the right to review information collected about you by this site. Contact the agency that provides the service you requested.

Secure Transmission  
For secured-data transmission, this site uses the industry standard encryption software, Secure Socket Layer (SSL). The URL in your browser will change to "HTTPS" instead of "HTTP" when this security feature is invoked. Your browser may also display a lock or key symbol on its task bar to indicate invoked secure transmission. If these indicators are not present, any information is susceptible to interception by other parties. Most Internet e-mail communication will not be secure. If you are communicating sensitive information, you might want to consider sending it in by postal mail.

Cookies  
A cookie file is a small text file created by a web site on your computer hard drive that contains unique information the site can use to track such things as passwords, lists of pages you´ve visited, the date when you last looked at a specific page or to identify your session at a particular web site. A cookie is often used in commercial sites to identify the items selected for a specific shopping cart application. If cookies are used on the web site their use will be clearly marked. While most browsers have an option that allows you to control the use of cookies, their use might provide some features that can not be used if cookies are turned off. Each application start page where cookies are used will have a specific statement that explains the use of the cookies, what information is being stored and whether the information is deleted or retained for future use when you complete your session.  
[www.oregon.gov](http://www.oregon.gov/) does not use cookies.

Oregon DMV Privacy & Information Disclosure Notice  
Thank you for visiting the OregonDMV.com web site. This notice addresses privacy concerns about the information collected on this site.

  The following topics are covered:

  1. Links to Other Sites - A Disclaimer
  2. Information Collected When You Just Browse
  3. Public Disclosure
  4. Personal Information and Nondisclosure
  5. Secure Transmission
  6. Cookies
  7. Asking questions about this policy

  **Links to Other Sites - A Disclaimer**

  This site has links to other web sites as a convenience to our customers. These include links to web sites operated by other government agencies, nonprofit organizations and private businesses. When you use one of these links, you are no longer on this site and this Privacy Notice will not apply. When you link to another web site, you are subject to the privacy policy of that new site.

  When you follow a link to one of these sites neither the State of Oregon, nor any agency, officer, or employee of the State of Oregon warrants the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of any information published by these external sites, nor endorses any content, viewpoints, products, or services linked from these systems, and can not be held liable for any losses caused by reliance on the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of their information. Portions of such information may be incorrect or not current. Any person or entity that relies on any information obtained from these systems does so at his or her own risk.  
Information Collected When You Just Browse If you do nothing during your visit to this web site but browse or download information, we automatically collect and store the standard data collected by all web server software. That information is as follows:

  1. The Internet Protocol (IP) address and domain name used (but not the e-mail address). The IP address is a numerical identifier assigned either to your Internet service provider or directly to your computer. We use the Internet IP to respond to your browser request. Example: 122.125.36.42;
  2. The Domain name (DNS) assigned on the Internet to your IP Address (if there is one). Example: somename.com;
  3. The type of browser and operating system you used. Example: Mozilla/4.0 (compatible; MSIE 4.01; Windows NT; IE4WDUS-1998101501);
  4. The date and time you visited this site;
  5. The web pages or services you accessed at this site;
  6. The web site you visited before coming to this web site (Note: this is included so that summary analysis can be done on how visitors get to our site, such as from a search engine or from a link on another site.); and
  7. The number of bytes sent by our server.

We do not track individual user navigation choices. We do, however, summarize the information listed above to determine:

  * The time it takes for our web server(s) to respond to your requests as you browse through our site
  * What organizations are our most frequent users (item 2 above) to better target our content for the audience
  * What browsers are being used on our site to determine what techniques we can use to develop pages that will work with different browsers (item 3 above)
  * How often our pages are being used (item 5 above)
  * By the traffic from other sites, such as the search engines that are good at directing people to our site (item 6 above)

For site security purposes and to ensure that this service remains available to all users, this site may monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage. If security monitoring reveals evidence of possible abuse or criminal activity, system personnel may provide the results of such monitoring to appropriate officials. Except for authorized law enforcement investigations, no attempts are made to identify individual users or their usage habits. Unauthorized attempts to upload information or change information on this service are strictly prohibited and may be punishable under the state law and federal statutes including the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986 and the National Information Infrastructure Protection Act of 1996.

    **Public Disclosure**

  The majority of information collected at this site becomes a public record. This includes Personal Information DMV may request from you in order to provide requested services. However, certain information may be protected from general release by one or more 

Oregon laws. These laws include Oregon's Public Records Law (Oregon Revised Statutes (ORS) 192.410-192.505) and DMV's Record Privacy Law (ORS 802.175-802.191). If information is protected under one of these laws, it will not be released unless a requestor qualifies to receive the information. (See Personal Information and Nondisclosure)  
Personal Information and Nondisclosure As defined in Oregon's Record Privacy Law, Personal Information means the following information that identifies an individual:

  * Driver License
  * Driver Permit or Identification Card Number
  * Name
  * Address (excluding five-digit zip code)
  * Telephone Number

Personal Information is protected from release under the Privacy Law. Generally, an individual cannot get another person's personal information. However, most businesses can get Personal Information if they have a specific need for the information that is permitted in the Privacy Law. A domain name and Internet Protocol (IP) address are not considered personal information, however, an email address may be considered personal information.

    **E-mail**

  If you send us an E-mail message with a question or comment that contains personal information, we will only use the information to respond to your request. However, please note that e-mails received from this site are considered public record. Certain information contained in the e-mail may be protected from general release under 

Oregon's Public Records Law (ORS 192.410-192.505) or Oregon's Record Privacy Law (ORS 802.175-802.191). This information may only be released if a requestor qualifies under the law to receive the information.

    **Forms**

  Each electronic form that collects personal information on this site will have a specific privacy statement or a link to the privacy statement that explains the conditions (if any) under which the information may be released to or shared with other parties.

    **Secure Transmission**

  For secured-data transmission, this site uses the industry standard encryption software, Secure Socket Layer (SSL). The URL in your browser will change to "HTTPS" instead of "HTTP" when this security feature is invoked. Your browser may also display a lock or key symbol on its task bar to indicate an invoked secure transmission. If these indicators are not present, any information is susceptible to interception by other parties. Most Internet e-mail communication will not be secure. If you are communicating sensitive information, you might want to consider sending it in by postal mail.

    **Cookies**

  A cookie is a small text file created by a web server and stored on your computer hard drive. ODOT uses cookies to collect non-personal information and data for site and session management purposes.

  These cookies are written in such a way that they are only used by our web site management tools or our web applications and these only read the cookies they place on your computer. They neither retrieve information from other cookie files, nor access any other information on your computer.

  With cookies it is possible to save unique information which the web server can then use either while you browse or when you return to the web site. Typical data saved in cookies are things such as your site preferences, the date when you last looked at a specific page or a random number used to identify your session at a particular web site.

  Also, cookies help us measure things like how many visitors come to our Web site, how many of these visitors are new and how many visitors are returning for a repeat visit.

  Cookies typically look like this:

  SITESERVER  
ID=064d02135eca4ee53c8954df74743696  
state.or.us/  
1024  
642859008  
31887777  
553863456  
29520789  
*

  If cookies are used on our web site for any other reason, their use will be clearly marked. The statement will specifically explain the use of the cookies, what information is being stored and whether the information is deleted or retained for future use when you complete your session.

  If you do not want information collected through the use of cookies, there is a simple procedure in most browsers allowing you to deny or accept the cookie feature (refer to your browser's help function for details). While most browsers have the option allowing you to control the use of cookies, doing so might result in some features on the site not working correctly.

    **Asking Questions about this Policy**

  If you have any questions about this policy, please 

_contact DMV_ [ _Link to DMV’s contact us page, currently at:<http://www.oregondmv.com/contactdmv/index.htm>_].
